# Jacey Pridgen | BSA Biology Honors

Location: 2810 Hemphill Park Apt 130 Austin, Texas

78705

Telephone: 214-499-0941

Email: Jacey.Pridgen@utexas.edu

# Professional profile

I have gained valuable experience as an undergraduate research assistant in the Dalby Lab and have gained a particular wealth of experience and skills in biochemical and cellular biology laboratory techniques. I will graduate in May 2020 from the University of Texas at Austin with a BSA degree in Honors Biology with Evidence and Inquiry and Pre-Health Professions for Science Majors certificates.

My important achievements have been presenting scientific posters for the Dalby Lab at various conferences; proposing, designing, and implementing an individual research project which culminated in a poster presentation during a summer research program; and recruiting and training my replacement for when I graduate the Dalby Lab.

# Education

- ➤ University of Texas at Austin from August 2017-May 2020
  - o GPA: 3.91
  - o 2020 MCAT: 517 (96th percentile)
  - o Honors Biology Bachelor of Science and Arts
    - Evidence and Inquiry Certificate
      - 22-hour certificate in which I designed my own field of study, "Health Practitioner and Patient Communication." During my third year, I will write an Honors Senior Thesis relating to the portrayal of clinical trials in popular media and how that portrayal impacts patient perception
    - Pre-Health Professions for Science Majors Certificate
      - 18-hour certificate intended for students interested in the health professions. This certificate helps to ensure I would be fully prepared for a future in medicine

# Placements and projects

## November 2017—June 2020

# Undergraduate Research Assistant in the Dalby Lab

### Outline

I assisted in several projects working under the most senior member in the lab using biochemical and cellular biology techniques

### Key responsibilities

- Making SDS-PAGE gels, preparing protein samples, and loading and running SDS-PAGE gels
- Blotting western blots as well as analyzing blot results
- Culturing, treating, and lysing mammalian cells
- Maintaining a sterile environment while completing cultured cell experiments
- Recruits and trains replacement as well as assists in the training of graduate students

### Key achievements

### Publications

Kaoud, T., Johnson, W., Ebelt, N., Piserchio, A., Zamora-Olivares, D., Ravenstein, S., **Jacey Pridgen**, Edupuganti, R, Sammons, R., Cano, M., Warthaka, M., Harger, M., Tavares, C., Park, J., Radwan, M., Ren, P., Anslyn, E., Tsai, K., Ghose, R., Dalby, K. "Modulating multifunctional ERK complexes by covalent targeting of a recruitment site in vivo." *Nature Communications* [In press]. 2019

Zamora-Olivares, D., Kaoud, T. S., Zeng, L., **Pridgen, J. R.,** Zhung, D.L., Ekpo, Y. E., Nye, J. R., Telles, M., Anslyn, E. V., Dalby, K. N. "Quantification of ERK kinase activity in biological samples using differential sensing" *ACS Chemical Biology* [In press]. 2019

### • Poster Presentations

Tamer S. Kaoud, William H. Johnson, Nancy D Ebelt, Andrea Piserchio, Jacey R. Pridgen, Diana Zamora-Olivares, Sabrina Van Ravenstein, Ramakrishna Edupuganti, Rachel Sammons, Micael Cano, Mangalika Warthaka, Pengyu Ren, Eric V. Anslyn, Kenneth Y Tsai, Ranajeet Ghose and Kevin N. Dalby, Targeting multi-functional ERK-protein complexes in vivo, LiveStrong Cancer Institute Basic and Translational Research Retreat, November 27th, 2018, LiveStrong Cancer Institute, Dell Medical School, University of Texas at Austin

Tamer S. Kaoud, **Jacey Pridgen**, Nancy D Ebelt, Jaeeun Go, Andrew Chen, Sabrina Van Ravenstein, Carla Van Den Berg, Austen F. Riggs, and Kevin N. Dalby, Regulation Of Jnk2 Activation By Self-Assocuiation, **University of Texas Longhorn Undergraduate Research Symposium**, April 17th, 2019, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas

Tamer S. Kaoud, **Jacey Pridgen**, Sabrina Van Ravenstein and Kevin N. Dalby, Investigating Proximity-Mediated Catalysis by a Protein Kinase: How Docking Affects MAPK Specificity and Processivity, **The 15th Annual "Louis C. Littlefield Celebrating Pharmacy Research Excellence" event**, April 17th, 2019, College of Pharmacy, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas

Diana Zamora-Olivares, Jacey R. Pridgen, Lingyu Zeng, Tamer S. Kaoud, Eric V. Anslyn, and Kevin N. Dalby, Quantification of ERK kinase activity in biological samples using differential sensing, LiveStrong Cancer Institute Basic and Translational Research Retreat, November 19th, 2019, LiveStrong Cancer Institute, Dell Medical School, University of Texas at Austin

Tamer S. Kaoud, Jacey R. Pridgen, Nancy D. Ebelt, Sabrina Van Raverstein, Lili Du, Kenneth Y Tsai, and Kevin N. Dalby, Down Regulation of the MKK4/JNK2 Axis in NSCLC Suppresses Tumor Growth and Metastasis, 16th Annual "Louis C. Littlefield Celebrating Pharmacy Research Excellence" event, April 15th, 2020 [Virtual], College of Pharmacy, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas

Diana Zamora-Olivares, **Jacey R. Pridgen**, Lingyu Zeng, Tamer S. Kaoud, Eric V. Anslyn and Kevin N. Dalby, Use of differential sensing-based biosensors to quantify ERK kinase activity in complex biological samples, **AACR Annual Meeting 2020**, June 13th, 2020, [Virtually Rescheduled]

## Oral Presentation

# 2019 Fall Undergraduate Research Symposium presented by the Molecular Biosciences Student Associations, September 28th, 2019, Austin, TX

Title: Modulating multi-functional ERK complexes by covalent targeting of a recruitment site in vivo

Session: Cell and Molecular Session 1

Awards

2nd Place undergraduate abstract award. 16th Annual "Louis C. Littlefield Celebrating Pharmacy Research Excellence" event, April 15th, 2020 [Virtual]

# May 2019—August 2019 Livestrong Cancer Institute Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship

#### Outline

I proposed, designed, implemented, and presented an independent research project relating to the field of oncology in the Vasquez Lab

### Key responsibilities

- Wrote a project proposal describing the aims of the project
- Cultured human cancer cells in liquid culture, maintaining a sterile, contamination free environment
- Completed mutagenesis assay in triplicate
- Sequenced and analysed sequencing results for mutants from mutagenesis assay
- Prepared and presented a poster in culmination of the project

## Key achievements

Winner of the Best Basic Science at the poster presentation session

# Awards, scholarships, and recognition

- ➤ University of Texas at Austin's College of Natural Science Scholarship August 2017 repeating annually
- ➤ College of Natural Science Second Year Excellence Award from the University of Texas at Austin's College of Natural Science March 2019
- College Scholar designation from the University of Texas at Austin's College of Natural Science May 2019
- ➤ Best Basic Science from Livestrong Cancer Institute Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship August 2019
- ➤ Jennie and Carl Sundberg Scholarship August 2019
- > AACR Undergraduate Scholar—Feb 2020
- National Cancer Institute's Cancer Research Training Award July 2020

# Work Experience

## O'JOY Juice and Yogurt Bar

August, 2017 – January, 2018

- Prepared fresh smoothies, juices and frozen yogurt
- Collected customer's payments and used a P.O.S. software

### **Dalby Laboratory**

January, 2018 – June, 2020

• Paid undergraduate research assistant

### **Pet Sitter**

- Cares for dogs, cats, and other household pets
- Manages personal small business

# Interests and Hobbies

### **Interests:**

- We are Blood
  - O I volunteer at We are Blood, a local blood distribution center that serves central Texas. I volunteer in the canteen, the area that blood donors come after they have donated. I rehydrate the donors and provide snacks, as well as monitor the donors for any symptoms of an adverse reaction to blood donation.
  - o I also regularly give blood when I am able
- Samaritan Health Ministries Volunteer
  - o I volunteer at Samaritan Health Ministries, a local clinic that serves uninsured patients within Williamson and Travis counties
  - o I help to check in and schedule patients using AthenaHealth. I also interact with patients to assist getting their financial paperwork in order.
- Pre-MD/PhD
  - o I plan to apply to an MD/PhD program in the summer of 2020

# **Hobbies:**

- Baking and cooking
- Interacting with animals of any kind
- Performing in a local band